Finding Aid for John B. Bennett papers, 1928-1964
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John B. Bennett papers 1928-1964
Bennett, John B. (John Bonifas), 1905-1964.
85529 Aa 2
Republican Congressman from Ontonagon in Michigan's Upper Peninsula. Correspondence, campaign materials, copies of bills introduced in Congress, and files concerning congressional reapportionment and the problems of the Upper Peninsula.
2 linear feet
0.98 GB
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Margaret Robinson (donor no. 5393 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
John Bonifas Bennett was a Representative from Michigan. He was born in Garden, Delta County, Mich. on January 10, 1904. He attended the public schools, and graduated from Watersmeet High School in Michigan, and from Marquette University Law School in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, in 1925. Bennett took a postgraduate course at Chicago, IL University Law School in 1926, and was admitted to the Wisconsin bar in 1925 and the Michigan bar in 1926. He practiced law in Ontonagon, Michigan from 1926-1942. Bennett was a prosecuting attorney of Ontonagon County from 1929-1934, deputy commissioner of the Michigan Department of Labor and Industry from 1935-1937, and was elected as a republican to the Seventy-eighty Congress from January 3, 1943-January 3, 1945. He was an unsuccessful candidate for reelection in 1944 to the Seventy-ninth Congress, and resumed the practice of law. In 1946, Bennett was elected to the Eightieth and to the eight succeeding Congresses and served from January 3, 1947, until his death, August 9, 1964.
The John B. Bennett collection has been arranged into the following series: Correspondence; Election and political materials; Congressional papers; Biographical; Photographs; and Sound recordings.
Subjects:
Apportionment (Election law)--Michigan.; Bennett, John B. (John Bonifas), 1905-1964.; Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen.; Finnish Americans--Michigan.; Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Ontonagon (Mich.); Republican Party (Mich.); Old age pensions--United States.; United States. Congress. House.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1953.; United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bennett, John B. (John Bonifas), 1905-1964.; Legislators--Michigan.; United States. Congress. House.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Bennett, John B. (John Bonifas), 1905-1964.; Elections--Michigan--1954.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Radio programs, Public service.; Social security--United States.; Radio in politics.; Upper Peninsula (Mich.); United States--Politics and government--1953-1961.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Contributors - Sound Recordings:
Knox, Victor Alfred, 1899-
Contributors:
Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Green, William, 1870-1952.; Hurja, Emil, 1892-; Lawrence, Howard Cyrus, 1890-1961.; Meany, George, 1894-1980.; Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.; National Association for the Advancement of the American Indian.; Woodruff, Roy Orchard, 1876-1953.
Genre:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - 1928 (Box 1)
  - 1932-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1945 (Box 1)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 1)
  - 1948-1950 (Box 1)
  - 1951-1957 (Box 1)
  - 1958-1960 (Box 1)
  - 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Letters of condolence 1964 (Box 1)
- Election and political materials
  - Election for prosecuting attorney of Ontonagon County
    - 1928 (Box 1)
    - 1932 (Box 1)
  - Election for Congressman
    - 1936 (Box 1)
    - 1938 (Box 1)
    - 1940 (Box 1)
    - 1942 (Box 1)
    - 1944 (Box 1)
    - 1946 (Speeches) (Box 1)
    - 1946 (Clippings) (Box 1)
    - 1948 (Box 1)
    - 1952 (Box 1)
    - 1954 (Box 1)
    - 1956 (Box 1)
    - 1958 (Box 1)
    - 1960, 1962 (Box 1)
    - 1964 (Box 1)
  - Campaign materials (general), 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Republican politics (general) (Box 1)
  - Election statistics (Box 1)
  - Reference file on Democratic legislator, John Sobol (Box 1)
- Congressional papers
  - Press releases (Box 1)
  - Speeches (general) (Box 1)
  - Congressional speeches, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Writings and articles (Box 1)
  - Bills introduced in Congress by Bennett
    - 78th Congress (Box 2)
    - 80th Congress (Box 2)
    - 81st Congress (Box 2)
    - 83rd Congress (Box 2)
    - 84th Congress (Box 2)
    - 85th Congress (Box 2)
    - 86th Congress, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - 87th Congress (Box 2)
    - 88th Congress (Box 2)
  - Congressional voting record
    - 86th Congress (Box 2)
    - 87th Congress (Box 2)
    - 88th Congress (Box 2)
  - Proposal to impose quota on importation of iron ore 1958-1962 (Box 2)
  - White Pine Copper Co. 1951-1953 (Box 2)
  - Michigan's Congressional Reapportionment 1963-1964, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Proposed establishment of a rocket launching site in the Upper Peninsula (newspaper clippings) 1962-1963 (Box 2)
  - Clippings and photographs concerning Congressional Committee tour of Latin America, 1951, 1 volumes (Box 2)
- Biographical
  - Bennett obituaries and eulogies, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Articles about Bennett in the newspaper Labor
    - 1952-1958 (Box 2)
    - 1959-1963 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous magazine articles containing references to Bennett (Box 2)
  - Printed miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea (Box 2)
- Photographs
  - Portraits (Box 2)
  - Group portraits, including presidential bill signings and Bennett participating in other Congressional activities (Box 2)
  - Portraits of other members of Michigan's Congressional delegation (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous: informal and campaign photos (Box 2)
  - Panoramic views: swearing-in ceremony, meeting of Congressional committee (Box 2)
- Sound recordings, 2 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes
  - Radio program with Bennett and congressman Victor A. Knox on the subject of social security, 1954 May, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 5 inch, 7 ½ ips
    - [Part 1], [85529-SR-1-1]; mp3 file; (Bennett and Knox discuss changes and amendments to the Social Security act.)
  - Campaign message discussing the issues of special relevance to the voters of the Upper Peninsula, 1954, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips
    - [Part 1], [85529-SR-2-1]; mp3 file; (Campaign message also discusses the Korean War, taxes, government spending, and mining.)
Selective Index to Correspondents
Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.
August 6, 1948
Green, William, 1870-1952.
June 22, 1944; April 30, 1946
Hurja, Emil, 1892-
October 27, 1944; December 12, 1944
Lawrence, Howard Cyrus, 1890-1961.
February 10, 1933
Meany, George, 1894-1980.
September 2, 1960.
Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.
December 18, 1944